C. Head talk - did you have to wear that? - I want to swim now!
–Måste du ha på dig det där? –Jag vill bada NU!
- I don't want to go. C. Head talk - it's final discussed. Lend a hand!
–Jag vill inte åka. –Det är slutdiskuterat. Hjälp till!
You can't be home alone for several weeks, you have to understand that.
Du kan inte vara ensam hemma i flera veckor, det måste du förstå.
- Dad, where will this be? C. Head talk - no, release the air first!
–Pappa, var ska den här vara? –Nej, släpp ur luften först!
-What are you doing? - You see that well.
–Vad håller du på med? –Det ser du väl.
- Here are the oars. - In in the caravan!
–Här är årorna. –In i husvagnen!
- Are you taking the pump? –Wa?
–Tar du med pumpen? –Va?
-Yes.
–TAR DU MED PUMPEN? –Ja.
C. The head talk here can you take the carriage?
Det här kan du väl ta i vagnen?
- We are a little late. C. Head talk - I know. Is it my fault?
–Vi är lite sena. –Jag vet. Är det mitt fel?
I want to swim, dad!
Jag vill bada, pappa!
C. Head talk, are you kind of C. Head talk and check the air in the rings?
Gun, är du snäll och kollar luften i ringarna?
C. Head talkative looks nice. C. Head chattering you take the other side?
Det ser fint ut. Kan du ta andra sidan?
C. Head Taper -resistant, can you drive a little, C. Head talk I can reach my car?
Ursäkta, kan du köra fram lite, så jag når att tanka min bil?
- If you calm down for a while. Okay? C. Head talk - Ok.
–Om du lugnar dig en stund. Okej? –Okej.
C. Head talk! It is only needed a little bit of C. Head talk to refuel. Do you drive forward?
Gun! Det behövs bara en liten bit för att tanka. Kör du fram?
C. Head talkative a little bit ...
Bara en liten bit...
C. Head talkative! A little more...
Framåt! Lite till...
C. Head talk! So yes.
Bra! Så ja.
What the hell!
Vad i helvete!
C. Head talk in hell is that question?
Vad i helvete är det frågan om?
C. Head Tapers What do you do ... huh?
Vad gör du... Va?
C. Head Taper Hörru You! This is my pump C. Head talk - take this one!
Hörru du! Det här är min pump – ta den här!
C. Head talk to me. But that C. Head talkative rug rolled straight in ...
Förlåt mig. Men den där raggarjäveln körde rakt i...
What did you say, the guy? Fucking road snail!
Vad sa du, grabben? Jävla landsvägssnigel!
C. Head Tapers -Bon Dragare! - Now damn!
–Bondraggare! –Nu jävlar!
What the hell are you doing, your fucking tatter?
Vad i helvete gör du, din jävla tattare?
- Damn Raggar forms! - Don't talk ... with those trolleys!
–Jävla raggarfasoner! –Snacka inte...med de brallorna!
C. Head talk at Grandpa! C. Head talk, he lies and sleeps.
Titta på morfar! Här ligger han och sover.
Hi dad. How are you? Are you ready?
Hej, pappa. Hur mår du? Är du klar?
Oh oh oh...
Oj, oj, oj...
- I thought it had happened. - It took some time, dad.
–Jag trodde det hade hänt nåt. –Det tog lite tid, pappa.
C. Head Precatejaja ... - aren't you done now?
Jaja... – Är du inte klar nu?
C. Head chattering do you have that on you? C. HOVE PATERVI WILL WILL ON vacation.
Ska du ha det där på dig? Vi ska på semester.
Yes.
Ja.
C. Head talkatives We try to get away, then?
Ska vi försöka komma i väg, då?
- Can we not stay here? -Do you want that?
–Kan vi inte stanna här? –Vill du det?
Yes. Rather than the disgusting caravan.
Ja. Hellre det än den äckliga husvagnen.
C. Head talkative - now. - If we would try to get away.
–Tyst nu. –Om vi skulle försöka komma i väg.
C. Head talkator, the fishermen are waiting ... C. The head talk was this one, huh?
Rudolf, fiskarna väntar... Det var den här, va?
Yes. And...
Ja. Och...
C. Head talk - do you have that with that one? - How does it manage otherwise?
–Ska du ha med den där? –Hur klarar den sig annars?
C. Head talk - clearly on the road. Nice, huh ... rudolf? - Yes, it's beautiful weather.
–Äntligen på väg. Skönt,va...Rudolf? –Ja, det är vackert väder.
C. Head talk, we should have it all the time.
Så ska vi ha det hela tiden.
C. Head talkative caravan we can go wherever C. Head talk. I call it vacation!
Med husvagnen kan vi åka vart vi vill. Det kallar jag semester!
C. Head talk free!
Frihet!
C. Head talk tare or how, little stump? C. Head talk with chin now.
Eller hur, lilla stumpan? Upp med hakan nu.
Finally, get together together - the whole family ...
Äntligen få vara tillsammans allihop – hela familjen...
It will be really nice.
Det ska bli riktigt skönt.
C. Head Precate. It's not possible. C. Head Precateevi comes too late here.
Nej. Det går inte. Vi kommer för sent här.
C. Head Precate Runs there. But do it, then!
Ni springer ditåt. Men gör det, då!
C. Head talkative self goes here c. Head talk and you call if you find it.
Jag går hitåt och så ropar ni om ni hittar den.
Wolfgang!
Wolfgang!
–Wolfgang ... —Tyst!
–Wolfgang... –Tyst!
Shut up!
Håll käften!
Gösta! Here it is - I've found it!
Gösta! Här är den – jag har hittat den!
C. Head talk that 141?
Är det 141?
C. Head talkator, do not scream C. Head talk at the campsite.
Rudolf, skrik inte på campingplatsen.
The C. Head talk is many who sleep C. Head talk at this time and they can wake up.
Det är många som sover vid den här tiden och de kan vakna.
C. Head talk of you sit there. I'll bed.
Kan du sätta dig där. Jag ska bädda.
C. Head talkative flower! Can you take it?
Blomman! Kan du ta den?
Why do I have to sleep on the floor?
Varför måste jag sova på golvet?
Dad, me and Johan sleep here and Grandpa sleeps over there.
Pappa, jag och Johan sover här och morfar sover där borta.
C. Head Tapers Little Girl Can Sleep C. Head Tapers on Rubber Matha?
Pappas lilla flicka kan väl sova på gummimadrass?
- Can I sleep in the tent? - It's too cold outside.
–Får jag sova i tältet? –Det är för kallt ute.
- Indians don't sleep in a caravan. C. Head talk - no, but you're not a Indian.
–Indianerna sover inte i husvagn. –Nej, men du är ingen indian.
C. Head Tapraredu is cowboy, as a father.
Du är cowboy, som pappa.
C. Head talkator, sit there for a while. C. Head talkative self should take a blanket here.
Rudolf, sitt där en stund. Jag ska ta ett täcke här.
C. Head talkative flower you can put there. - I start to get dizzy from blowing.
–Blomman kan du sätta där. –Jag börjar bli yr av att blåsa.
C. Head talkator, give her the pump! The C. Head Pratared is in the cabinet under the flower.
Rudolf, ge henne pumpen! Den är i skåpet under blomman.
- But the cabinet is locked. C. Head talk - Locked? Wait, you should see.
–Men skåpet är låst. –Låst? Vänta, ska du få se.
- Can the flower remain? C. Head talk - yes. Sit, so I'll arrange this.
–Kan blomman vara kvar? –Ja. Sitt, så ska jag ordna det här.
C. Head talk! It's a security barrier here.
Titta! Det är en säkerhetsspärr här.
The C. mainspratared is because it doesn't ... Going up C. Head talk here ... when you go.
Det är för att det inte...går upp här...när man åker.
C. Head Tapers are the fucking pump? C. Head talkative is not here anyway.
Var är den jävla pumpen? Den är inte här i alla fall.
C. The head talk is a barrier here too ...
Det är en spärr här också...
C. Head talk - not here! Where can it be? - Maybe in the cabinet there.
–Inte här! Var kan den vara? –Kanske i skåpet där.
C. Head talkative here is not. C. Head talkative not that we forgot it!
Här är den inte. Säg inte att vi har glömt den!
- Now I shit in this! - Help for here.
–Nu skiter jag i det här! –Hjälp till här.
C. Head Precate, Rudolf! You should do this in this not to do this - think about the "pump".
Nej, Rudolf! Det här ska du inte göra – tänk på "pumpen".
C. Head talk not on it when I blow!
Gå inte på den när jag blåser!
Dad, I'm tired.
Pappa, jag är trött.
C. Head Precate, this is not possible. C. HOVA PATERVI makes this systematically.
Nej, det här går inte. Vi gör det här systematiskt.
C. Head talkative box box! C. Head talkative pump!
Jävla låda! Förbannade pump!
So nice that we are finally on our way ...
Så skönt att vi äntligen är på väg...
... and that you take care of dad ... so nice ...
...och att du tar hand om pappa...så fint...
He is so alone.
Han är så ensam.
It means a lot to him to accompany us ... to meet the kids ...
Det betyder mycket för honom att följa med oss...att träffa barnen...
No ... Gösta!
Nej... Gösta!
They can wake up!
De kan vakna!
C. Head talkatives anyway ... Four week vacation!
Skönt ändå... Fyra veckors semester!
C. Head talkative four wonderful weeks. In the caravan.
Fyra härliga veckor. I husvagnen.
C. sounds
SNARKNINGAR
C. Head talk this!
Ta den här!
- Where should this stand? - On the sink.
–Var ska den här stå? –På diskbänken.
Andiamo, é tardi!
Andiamo, é tardi!
Mom, Vai Dentro!
Mamma, vai dentro!
Jean!
Jean!
Jean !!
Jean!!
--Je ne suis pas un artist. –Ce n'est pas la question.
–Je ne suis pas un artist. –Ce n'est pas la question.
Thanks. - From Gutterne!
Tack. – Fra gutterne!
C. Head talkative I knew it well! C. The head talk was something we had forgotten.
Jag visste väl det! Det var nånting vi hade glömt.
He can't be far away.
Han kan inte vara långt borta.
Madame Peugot! Please, contact the reception.
Madame Peugot! Please, contact the reception.
You! Fried perch, that's the best thing I know.
Du! Stekt abborre, det är det bästa jag vet.
Mr. Rudolf Johansson! Please contact the reception.
Herr Rudolf Johansson! Var vänlig kontakta receptionen.
- Don't you Rudolf Johansson? -Yes.
–Heter inte du Rudolf Johansson? –Jo.
- Then they call you in the speaker. -Oh really.
–Då ropar de på dig i högtalaren. –Jaså.
C. Head Taper Done You Nothing?!
Hör du ingenting?!
C. Head talkative here we have been looking like madmen! C. Head Precate you move on the pans, we're going away.
Här har vi letat som galningar! Nu rör du på påkarna, vi ska i väg.
Bowl! And thank you.
Skål! Och tack ska du ha.
- Do you have to drive so damn fast? C. Head talk - 70. It's a good march speed.
–Måste du köra så jävla fort? –70. Det är en bra marschfart.
C. Head talk of those two! C. Head talkativesandem cyclists ...
Titta på de där två! Tandemcyklisterna...
The C. Head talk is also a way to vacation. C. Head Tableman should not be in a hurry ...
Det är också ett sätt att semestra. Man ska inte ha bråttom...
- But you get fitness. C. Head talk - look, how they drive!
–Men man får kondition. –Titta, hur de kör!
C. Head talkative not strange that many C. Head talk accidents happen. Why are they in such a hurry?
Inte konstigt att det händer många olyckor. Varför har de så bråttom?
C. Head talk here!
Titta här!
C. Head talkative self creeps in 30 ... C. Head talkative thinking to prevent traffic so!
Jag kryper i 30... Tänk att hindra trafiken så!
C. HOVA PATEREDE SHOULD BE CONSIDERED C. HEAD PREPRATERI The holiday traffic!
De borde vara förbjudna i semestertrafiken!
But it's not a bad caravan.
Men det är ingen dålig husvagn.
-Be careful! C. Head talk - fucking road -snail!
–Var försiktig! –Jävla väg–snigel!
C. Head talkators you we can do it? No. C. Head talkative "We collaborate in traffic" ...
Tror ni vi klarar det? Nej. "Vi samarbetar i trafiken"...
C. Head talk they could go aside a bit. C. Head talk in the middle of the road like that!
Om de kunde åka åt sidan lite. Ligga mitt i vägen så där!
C. Head Precate Vi MUST RUN OM! C. Head talk can carry or burst.
Vi måste köra om! Det får bära eller brista.
C. Head talk!
Ja!
C. Head talk? So they should be taken.
Såg du? Så ska de tas.
-I have to pee. C. Head talkative - va?
–Jag måste kissa. –Va?
- But not now, Dad!
–Men inte nu, pappa!
-I must. C. Head talk - Ok.
–Jag måste. –Okej.
C. Head talkative bastards!
Jävlar!
C. Head talkators do you now, what he puts up with?
Ser du nu, vad han ställer till med?
- Should we drink a cup of coffee? - Can we get coffee?
–Ska vi dricka en kopp kaffe? –Får vi kaffe?
C. Head talkative - Nice in life! We do not have time. - I have to poop, dad.
–Aldrig i livet! Vi har inte tid. –Jag måste bajsa, pappa.
C. Head talk - but stay! -I can not.
–Men håll dig! –Jag kan inte.
-Dad! There is frog fry here. C. Head talk - yes, yes.
–Pappa! Det finns grodyngel här. –Ja, ja.
- Don't go too close to the road! - It was good coffee, Gun.
–Gå inte för nära vägen! –Det var gott kaffe, Gun.
- What is this for a button? C. Head talk - What then?
–Vad är det här för en knapp? –Vad då?
C. Head talk, so it? It is nothing. C. Head talk it on automatic, Little Stumpan.
Jaså den? Det är ingenting. Ha den på automatik, lilla stumpan.
Jean!
Jean! Jean!
C. Head talk we do not have time to sit here.
Nu har vi inte tid att sitta här.
C. Head talkative - rudolf, do you throw it in the trash can? -Yes.
–Rudolf, slänger du den i soptunnan? –Ja.
C. Head Taperselotta! You help with the chairs.
Lotta! Du hjälper till med stolarna.
C. Head talk, now you come here! C. Head talk we will travel.
Johan, nu kommer du hit! Nu ska vi resa.
C. Head talk area!
Aj!
The garbage can is full.
Soptunnan är full.
Now I get hold of you!
Nu feck jag tag i dej!
Don't just get from the town on shit 'down!
Inte bara komma frå stan å skit' ner!
I shoot 'off both legs!
Jag skjut' av dej bägge bena!
How do you think the cows feel, when they get glass in the grove, huh?
Hur tror du korna mår, då de få glas i klöjven, va?
On the animals in small shades? Togs that you would really shoot 'the bowl!
Å djuren i småskugen? Töcke som du sku' man egentligen skjut' skåln av!
Do you think we could tolerate to this?
Tror du att vi konna tolerära sånt?
Man sku 'slide' the bowl of you!
Man sku' skjut' skåln av dej!
They are too damn good. They are just starting to pick up now.
De ä' ju för jävligt. De ä' bara börja å plock opp nu.
C. Head Tapers WEEP UP THE BOX, RUDolf!
Veva upp rutan, Rudolf!
- Cast! Supports the rear view mirrors ... C. Head Tapers - fan!
–Gösta! Klarar sig backspeglarna... –Fan!
C. HOVE PATERAHH!
Ahh!
- Gösta ... - Dad!
–Gösta... –Pappa!
C. Head Tapers Jävlar!
Jävlars!
It was good, Gun.
Det var gott, Gun.
-A little more? -Yes thank you.
–Lite mer? –Ja tack.
- Yes? -I am full.
–Johan? –Jag är mätt.
And so a little lingonberry.
Och så lite lingon.
Shouldn't you have some food, honey? It is good.
Ska du inte ha lite mat, älskling? Det är gott.
Don't you like cabbage dolls, Gösta?
Tycker du inte om kåldolmar, Gösta?
- Dad is so bad. - It's right for him.
–Pappa har så ont. –Det är rätt åt honom.
He has an unfortunate ability to complicate everything.
Han har en olycklig förmåga att krångla till allt.
And he is not particularly handy.
Och särskilt händig är han inte.
Grandpa, do you remember when Dad was breaking your tractor?
Morfar, minns du när pappa körde sönder din traktor?
If I were to put on some coffee ...
Om jag skulle sätta på lite kaffe...
- I want to get stuck in the laundry. - He is your dad anyway.
–Jag önskar han fastnat i tvätten. –Han är i alla fall din pappa.
He thinks he knows best.
Han tror att han vet bäst.
He is not so easy.
Han har det inte så lätt.
He wants us to have a nice holiday.
Han vill att vi ska ha en trevlig semester.
- I would have had to stay home. -Yes Yes.
–Jag skulle ha fått stanna hemma. –Ja, ja.
You can try to be a little kind.
Du kan väl försöka vara lite snäll.
Next summer you may not be.
Nästa sommmar är du kanske inte med.
- You are soon big now. - But he doesn't notice.
–Du är snart stor nu. –Men det märker inte han.
It's only a few weeks left now. We still have it pretty wonderful.
Det är bara några veckor kvar nu. Vi har det ändå ganska härligt.
Differently than at home.
Annorlunda än hemma.
You're really good. - Gösta, join now! You can stand in the goal.
Du är riktigt duktig. – Gösta, var med nu! Du kan stå i målet.
C. sound high pop music
HÖG POPMUSIK
C. Head talkative you kick ball here? People want C. Head talkatives from having some calm on their vacation.
Måste ni sparka boll här? Folk vill kanske ha lite lugn på sin semester.
- Are you with, Grandpa? -I can not take it. Grandpa is tired.
–Är du med, morfar? –Jag orkar inte mer. Morfar är trött.
- Dad, do you play football with me? C. Head talk - I don't feel good.
–Pappa, spelar du fotboll med mig? –Jag mår inte bra.
- Let dad be at peace. - Can we not swim, then?
–Låt pappa vara i fred. –Kan vi inte bada, då?
-What are you doing? -! Pee and lie down ...
–Vad gör du? –Äh! Kissa och lägg dig...
Lotta has a hubby! - Look, Dad!
Lotta har en fästman! Lotta har en fästman! – Titta, pappa!
- Lotta has a hubby. C. Head talk - yeah?! You haven't said anything about that.
–Lotta har en fästman. –Jaså?! Det har du inte sagt nåt om.
C. Head talk - What is he called, then? -I know. His name is Lasse.
–Vad heter han, då? –Jag vet. Han heter Lasse.
-Lasse ... - now, Gösta!
–Lasse... –Sluta nu, Gösta!
Don't you understand that the girl is getting sad?
Förstår inte du att flickan blir ledsen?
- Look, mom! - In the refrigerator.
–Titta, mamma! –In i kylskåpet.
C. Head talk - hurry now, Gun! - Where should you go?
–Skynda dig nu, Gun! –Vart ska ni ta vägen?
Into town and shop. Gösta wants something strong against the headaches.
In till stan och handla. Gösta vill ha nåt starkt mot huvudvärken.
Well, should you buy out? - Gösta!
Jaså, ska ni köpa ut? – Gösta!
Do you want to be kind and buy a half for me?
Vill du vara snäll och köpa en halva åt mig?
C. Head talkative response is that satan system? C. Head talk noise is not able to.
Var ligger det satans systemet? Vi hinner inte.
Take it easy.
Ta det lugnt.
Where!
Där!
Beware the cyclist! But not here!
Akta cyklisten! Men inte här!
C. Head talk I know!
Nu vet jag!
C. Head talk You loosen the handbrake, C. Head talk we swing.
Om du lossar handbromsen, så gungar vi.
C. Head Tapervi swings back and forth, C. Head Taper So we come out.
Vi gungar fram och tillbaka, så kommer vi ut.
C. Head talk! We're coming now...
Åh! Nu kommer vi...
Gösta!
Gösta!
C. Head talk! You!
Hej! Du!
C. Head talkative you can come here a blow?
Hej! Skulle du kunna komma hit ett slag?
C. Head talkative a small stroke.
Bara ett litet slag.
C. Head talkative here - take this one. We are stuck.
Här – ta den här. Vi sitter fast.
C. Head talkative purchase a whole explorer and keep the C. Head talkative loss! We will not come out.
Köp en hela Explorer och behåll resten! Vi kommer inte ut.
C. Head talk - they close soon. -Of course.
–De stänger snart. –Ja visst.
C. Head Tapraredu! That is where!
Du! Det är där!
C. Head Precate what are you doing? Where are you going? C. Head talkatives cursed ...
Vad gör du? Vart går du? Din förbannade...
-Wait! I'm just going to go now. C. Head talk - ni there. Hello!
–Vänta! Jag ska just åka nu. –Ni där. Hallå!
C. Head talkatively someone! Can you help us?
Äntligen någon! Kan ni hjälpa oss?
C. Head Precate, No. We have not parked here C. Head talk - we are trapped!
Nej, nej. Vi har inte parkerat här – vi är instängda!
C. HOVA PATERVI cannot come out and therefore C. Head talk we have not been able to stop in anything!
Vi kan inte komma ut och därför har vi inte kunnat stoppa i nåt!
C. Head Tapers ...
Nej...
- Don't you have a splash, Gösta? C. Head talk - no.
–Ska du inte ha en skvätt, Gösta? –Nej.
- It can be seen ... - no, then. Come now!
–Det syns... –Nej, då. Kom nu!
C. Head talk - Now I can no longer cope. - Was a little calm, Gösta.
–Nu orkar jag inte längre. –Var lite lugn, Gösta.
C. Head talk - why did he go? - We are struggling in it. Darling...
–Varför skulle han med? –Nu struntr vi i det. Älskling...
No, Gösta. Gösta!
Nej, Gösta. Gösta!
C. Head talk, what a holiday! Huh ...?
Åh, vilken semester! Va...?
C. HOVE PATERVI has not been together C. Head Tapraredu and I for fourteen days.
Vi har inte fått vara tillsammans du och jag på fjorton dar.
C. Head Tapers, Gun! Don't wake him up.
Nej, Gun! Väck honom inte.
- But here he can't sleep? C. Head talk - it doesn't matter. Come now.
–Men här kan han ju inte sova? –Det gör väl inget. Kom nu.
C. Head talk - Hi, kids! -Hi dad. Come and read the Phantom.
–Hej, ungar! –Hej, pappa. Kom och läs Fantomen.
C. Head talk. I have a surprise.
Vänta. Jag har en överraskning.
Look, that's the tent!
Titta, det är ju tältet!
C. Head talkative self had thought that you would be C. Head talk in the tent tonight.
Jag hade tänkt att ni skulle få sova i tältet i natt.
- you?! -I want to sleep with you.
–Va?! –Jag vill sova med dig.
C. Head talk - we brought the tent for your sake. - I want to sleep with you and mom.
–Vi tog ju med tältet för din skull. –Jag vill sova med dig och mamma.
C. Head talkum you have done the whole holiday. C. Head talk not Indians sleep in a caravan?
Det har du gjort hela semestern. Inte sover indianer i husvagn?
I'm not a Indian.
Jag är ingen indian.
Good morning.
God morgon.
-Dad! I want to bathe. C. Head talk - We are not able to now.
–Pappa! Jag vill bada. –Vi hinner inte nu.
-Why not? C. Head talk - but quiet now!
–Varför inte? –Men tyst nu!
There will be nothing bathing for you this summer - and no fishing either.
Det blir inget bada för dig i sommar – och inget fiske heller.
Grandpa says we should never bathe. You are giant!
Morfar säger att vi aldrig ska bada. Du är jättedum!
-Stop now! - Dad, Lotta strikes me!
–Sluta nu! –Papppa, Lotta slår mig!
Stop now, both! Dad drives.
Sluta nu, bägge två! Pappa kör.
Mother! Mother...
Mamma! Mamma...
How is it?
Hur är det?
Ruotsi ... Sweden!
Ruotsi...Sverige!
Ruotsi!
Ruotsi!
Hurray! HURRAY!
Hurra! HURRA!
- Dad, my ball! C. Head talk - What is it?
–Pappa, min boll! –Vad är det?
- My ball! - My sandwich! It is ruined.
–Min boll! –Min smörgås! Den är förstörd.
C. Head talkative - here. - It can't be eaten.
–Här. –Den går inte att äta.
C. Head talk! Go to mom now. C. Head talk - What was it?
Så! Gå till mamma nu. – Vad var det?
My ball is gone. Not there. Where!
Min boll är borta. Inte där. Där!
- It's the wrong ball. C. Head talk - It doesn't matter. This one is finer.
–Det är ju fel boll. –Det gör inget. Den här är finare.
- It's not mine. C. Head Tapers - play now! I blow up the mattress.
–Den är inte min. –Lek nu! Jag blåser upp madrassen.
-I want to bathe. C. Head talk - first rubber mattress, huh?
–Jag vill bada. –Först gummimadrassen, va?
- You can fish with me. - I don't want to fish, I want to swim.
–Du kan få fiska med mig. –Jag vill inte fiska, jag vill bada.
- Dad, Blow this up too. C. Head talk - not two things at the same time!
–Pappa, blås upp den här också. –Inte två saker samtidigt!
-I do not want to. C. Head talk - but bathe now.
–Jag vill inte. –Men bada nu.
No one else bathes. I do not want to!
Ingen annan badar. Jag vill inte!
C. Head talkative self understands nothing. For two weeks c. Head talk, you have been chatting about this. Bathe!
Jag förstår inget. I två veckor har du tjatat om det här. Bada!
It's cold.
Det är kallt.
Please, Matilda. We're going home now.
Snälla, Matilda. Vi ska gå hem nu.
Grandfather freezes. Matilda, stop now!
Farfar fryser. Matilda, sluta nu!
Now we have to go home.
Nu måste vi gå hem.
No, Matilda! Remove the bucket!
Nej, Matilda! Ta bort hinken!
Grandfather!
Farfar!
C. Head talk area!
Aj!
C. HOVA PATERAH! Fy thousand, so nice!
Ah! Fy tusan, så skönt!
C. HOVA PATERA, RUDolf ... C. Head Taper Here you have a lot of nature, huh?
Nå, Rudolf... Här har du mycket natur, va?
- Yes, I go fishing. C. Head Tapers - Wait with it. First the TV antenna.
–Ja, jag går och fiskar. –Vänta med det. Först tv–antennen.
-Yes! I want to watch TV. C. Head talkative - the guy so gladly want.
–Ja! Jag vill se på tv. –Grabben vill så gärna.
C. Head Tapers Aid for, so it goes fast!
Hjälp till, så går det fort!
C. Head talk - Now I'm done. -Hurry up!
–Nu är jag klar. –Snabba dig!
C. Head talk - å ... Oops. - Near good, dad. Hurry up!
–Å... Hoppsan. –Nästan bra, pappa. Snabba dig!
C. Head talk - Is it good? -No. Go back. So!
–Är det bra? –Nej. Gå tillbaka. Så!
- It jumps. - Now it rolls!
–Det hoppar. –Nu rullar det!
C. Head talk - release after ... C. Head talk - Now it jumps again.
–Släpp efter... –Nu hoppar det igen.
- It is still rolling! - It was better before. - Dad!
–Det rullar fortfarande! –Det var bättre förut. – Pappa!
Good!
Bra!
... folds the body together and gets a perfect stroke. What a hope!
...viker ihop kroppen och får ett perfekt nerslag. Vilket hopp!
We probably get it in reprise.
Vi får det nog i repris.
Here - see the perfect rise! The perfect ankle…
Här – se det perfekta upphoppet! Den perfekta vriststräckningen...
... and then the stroke.
...och sen nerslaget.
32.80, please.
32,80, tack.
Don't poke in the food!
Peta inte i maten!
C. Head Tapers62.75!
62,75!
- I want barbecue sausage. C. Head talk - Now you eat.
–Jag vill ha grillkorv. –Nu äter du.
- Why does she get a barbecue sausage? C. Head talk - Now you eat, otherwise damn!
–Varför får hon grillkorv? –Nu äter du, annars jävlar!
Gösta!
Gösta!
- MMM ... —Hon tease, dad.
–Mmm... –Hon retas, pappa.
- Don't get her. Eat! -I dont want. She is teased again.
–Bry dig inte om henne. Ät! –Jag vill inte ha. Hon retas igen.
Lotta, stop teasing!
Lotta, sluta retas!
- damn! C. Head talkative - Hell for hell!
–Jävlar! –Ät för helvete!
- Damn old man! C. Head talk - hold mouth!
–Jävla gubbe! –Håll mun!
It is not possible.
Det går ju inte.
You're not really wise, shit guy!
Du är inte riktigt klok, skitgubbe!
C. Head talk - not another sound! - Now I have had a headache.
–Inte ett ljud till! –Nu har jag fått ont i huvudet.
C. Head talkative do you not eat? C. Head Tapraredu has no food.
Varför äter inte du? Du har ingen mat.
- No urgency for me. C. Head talk - why don't you take a "today's"?
–Ingen brådska för min del. –Varför tar du inte en "dagens"?
C. The head talk is only to sabotage. C. The head talk is the last time you are with!
Det är bara för att sabotera. Det är sista gången som du är med!
C. Head Tapers - Sabotage! - A cobbler box.
–Sabotage! –En skomakarlåda.
C. Head talk here is not wise ...
Det här är inte klokt...
C. Head Tapershon is gone! - Get in the car! - C. Head talkative self has to go to the police.
Hon är borta! – Sätt dig i bilen! – Jag måste i väg till polisen.
-I can not take it. C. Head talk - put yourself in the caravan.
–Jag orkar inte. –Lägg dig i husvagnen.
- It is prohibited. C. Head talk - I drive carefully, little old man.
–Det är förbjudet. –Jag kör försiktigt, lilla gumman.
We are in a hurry. To the police!
Nu har vi bråttom. Till polisen!
- Where can she be? C. Head talk - she is gone!
–Var kan hon vara? –Hon är borta!
- I have to lighten the bladder. C. Head talk - not again! You don't do anything else.
–Jag måste lätta på blåsan. –Inte nu igen! Du gör inget annat.
Gösta, I can't stay anymore.
Gösta, jag kan inte hålla mig längre.
No!
Nej!
Stay! Gösta ...
Stanna! Gösta...
STAY! STOP!
STANNA! STOPP!
-My husband! The caravan - over there! -Jump up!
–Min man! Husvagnen – där borta! –Hoppa upp!
- She never comes back. C. Head talk - Tyst!
–Hon kommer aldrig tillbaka. –Tyst!
- Look, it's mom! C. Head talk - what the hell?!
–Titta, det är mamma! –Vad i helvete?!
The police ...
Polisen...
- From the county traffic group. C. Head talk - so good that you came!
–Från Länstrafikgruppen. –Så bra att ni kom!
C. Head talkative daughter has disappeared. C. Head Precatee Vi struggled ...
Min dotter har försvunnit. Vi bråkade...
Well. I have followed you. You go way too fast with the caravan.
Jaha. Jag har följt efter dig. Du åker alldeles för fort med husvagnen.
C. Head talkative wife Mrs. Motorcycle. It was C. Head talk after this with ... the tavern and ...
Min fru åker motorcykel. Det var efter det här med...tavernan och...
C. Head Tapershon lay in the back of ...
Hon låg bak i...
We're talking about that later. I want to look at your driver's license first.
Vi pratar om det där sen. Jag vill titta på ditt körkort först.
C. Head talkative self would drive so gently ...
Jag skulle köra så försiktigt...
C. Head Tapers I probably have it here at the back, C. Head Tapersvi changed pants before we went ...
Jag har det antagligen här bak, vi bytte ju byxor innan vi for...
C. Head talk, then, then? C. Head talk - think she would disappear ...
Vart ska du, då? – Tänk att hon skulle försvinna...
First the speeding, then we talk about your problems.
Först fortkörningen, sen pratar vi om dina problem.
C. Head talkative not enough ... The motorcycle ... 150 ...
Inte fort nog...motorcykeln...150...
- Can I look at your driver's license? C. Head talk - she disappeared ... on the tavern ...
–Får jag titta på ditt körkort? –Hon försvann...på tavernan...
Now I want to look at the driver's license!
Nu vill jag titta på körkortet!
Thanks. I'll keep it for a while.
Tack. Jag behåller det ett tag.
- You haven't been drinking alcohol? C. Head talk - not a drop!
–Du har inte druckit sprit? –Inte en droppe!
C. Head talkative self does not drive ... Drum drank.
Jag kör inte...druckit inte.
- I will let you do an alcohol test. C. Head talk - I thank you.
–Jag ska låta dig göra en alkotest. –Jag tackar.
C. Head talk - There Grandpa disappears too! - He is doing well. We're doing this now.
–Där försvinner morfar också! –Han klarar sig. Vi gör det här nu.
C. Head talk is all three ...
Nu är det alla tre...
You fill your lungs with air and then fill the balloon with a breath.
Du fyller dina lungor med luft och fyller sen ballongen med ett andetag.
You are welcome.
Var så god.
C. Head talkum he is! What did I say?
Där är han! Vad var det jag sa?
-Grandfather! -Dad!
–Morfar! –Pappa!
C. HOVA PATERVI is here now. Come here!
Vi är här nu. Kom hit!
C. Head talkative - grandfather, come ashore now! -Dad!
–Morfar, kom in i land nu! –Pappa!
C. Head Precateerudolf! Rudolf ...
Rudolf! Rudolf...
C. Head talkative here! Do you hear me?!
Kom hit! Hör du vad jag säger?!
Fucking old man ...
Kom hit! Jävla gubbe...
C. Head Tapraredu destroys the entire holiday for us!
Du förstör hela semestern för oss!
SWEDISH SUPPORT: Lisbet Olofsdotter (C) Swedish Television AB 2006
Svensktextning: lisbet olofsdotter (c) Sveriges Television AB 2006